now I want you to observe something
about all of these different sets that
I've been talking about so you're just
one such example that we've been looking
at this is the even integers notice
however that the inside of my definition
of the even integers began n is an
element of the integers such that some
property is true so this a in its
definition is sort of living within the
larger set of this integers and this was
going to introduce this to the idea of a
universal set so imagine I just have
some sets floating around I got my a
I've got my B but what domain what
contents do we have are we talking about
integers are we talking about people or
we're talking about functions where are
we broadly living what's our larger
context so what we have is the notion of
a universe and we usually denote it by
this a big square box on the outside we
call it you for universe here and all of
the sets that we're talking about are
all contained within this sort of larger
contextual set in other words we're
going to say that the universe U is the
larger context for whatever we are
talking about it's just some big set and
all of the other sets are subsets of it
and then we can do an operation if we
know what the universal set is going to
be so for example let me just take one
set a and it's living inside of the
universal set I can define something
where I set a notice I put a little C up
here this stands for complement I'm
claiming that a complement is not a it's
all this stuff over here
all of the stuff which is around my set
a and all of the things that are not in
a but are still broadly in my universe
so for example what is the complement of
the even integers well it does depend on
what my universe is as the complement of
the even integers like within the all of
the integers is going to be the odd
integers right every integer that is not
even as odd so if my universe is
all of the integers the complement of
the evens is the odd but if my broader
universe that I'm considering is all
real integers things like pies and
things like 1/2 then the complement of
the even integers include the odd
integers but includes all of those other
rational and irrational numbers as well
that are not even integers so what
universe you're talking into is usually
contextually understood or perhaps
explicitly written down and if you know
what the universe is you can take the
complement of a set within a particular
universe